A Guide to the Marian Van Landigham Papers, 1979-2006
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Marian Van Landingham Papers, 1979-2006
The Library of Virginia
42474
13.225 cubic feet (29 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Portions of the Subject Files are restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78. Restricted information in this collection has been sealed but not removed from the collection. The specific material that has been closed is noted in the Contents List of this guide.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Marian Van Landingham, Alexandria.
Biographical Information
Marian Van Landingham was born in Albany, Georgia on 10 September 1937. She graduated from Druid Hills High School in Atlanta in 1955, and then studied political science at Emory University, earning a bachelor's degree in 1959 and a master's degree in 1960. Van Landingham worked in public relations, and in 1967 she moved to Arlington County, Virginia to take a position as an information specialist at the National Air Pollution Agency, a forerunner to the Environmental Protection Agency. She then served as a press aide to Rep. Phil Landrum (D-GA). In 1972, Van Landingham moved to Alexandria. She was also president of the Art League, and became involved in efforts to restore the vacant torpedo plant and turn it into studio space for Alexandria area artists. Van Landingham ran for City Council in 1979, but was defeated by only 800 votes. In 1981, she waged a succesful campaign for a seat in the Virginia House of Delegates, and began a career in the General Assembly that would continue for 23 years. She was the first woman to chair the Privileges and Elections Committee, and by the time she retired, she was the most senior woman serving in the House. In 2005, Van Landingham decided not to run for re-election due to health concerns. She continues to maintain her studio at the Torpedo Factory Art Center, and is involved in various philanthropic and humanitarian activities in Alexandria.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1979-2006, of Marian Van Landingham (b. 1937) of Alexandria, Virginia, who represented the 45th District in the Virginia House of Delegates from 1982 to 2005. Includes legislative files, subject files, "white" files, and campaign files.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I. Legislative Files.
II. Subject Files.
III. "White" Files.
IV. Campaign Files.
Contents List
- Series I. Legislative Files, 1982-2005., Extent: 15 boxes. (Box 1-15)
  The legislative files include drafts and final copies of bills, resolutions, and budget amendments introduced by Van Landingham, correspondence with constituents, fellow legislators, advocacy groups, and government officials, background materials, clippings, notes, memoranda, summaries, legal opinions, roll call votes, and impact statements. There are also patron and co-patron reports generated by the House Clerk which give summmaries, dates, and actions taken by the General Assemby on legislation introduced or co-sponsored by Van Landingham. Areas of interest reflected in the legislation she introduced include consumer services protection, election laws, funding for the arts, gun control, historic preservation, parental leave, parole eligibility, spousal abuse and rape crisis centers, telecommunications, tenant rights, and youth programs. There is only a small amount of material for 1993, and none for 1994, 1996, and 1998.
  Arranged chronologically by year.
  - 1982
    - Patron: House Bills. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Co-Patron Report. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Co-Patron: House Bills. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Co-Patron: House Resolutions. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Co-Patron: House Joint Resolutions. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Co-Patron: Senate Bills. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Co-Patron: Senate Joint Resolutions. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Civil Court Jurisdiction. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Condominiums. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Gun Control. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Landlord/Tenant. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Preliminary Hearings. (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
    - Private Relief Bills. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1983
    - Patron Report. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Co-Patron Report. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Co-Patron Bills. (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
    - H.B. 426 - Court Orders Pending Divorce or Annulment Suits. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - H.B. 508 - Forms of Ballots. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - H.B. 509 - Duties of General Registrar. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - H.B. 510 - Landlord Disclosure. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - H.B. 511 - Relocation Expenses for Displaced Tenants. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - H.B. 512 - Security Deposits. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - H.B. 615 - Uranium Mining Permits. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - H.J.R. 51 - Homestead Exemption. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - H.J.R. 62 - Constitutional Amendment on Tax Assessments. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - H.J.R. 63 - Study of Changes in Telecommunications Insdustry. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Committees. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Wiretapping. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1984
    - Patron Report. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Co-Patron Report. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Co-Patron Bills. (Box 2, Folder 19-22)
    - H.B. 365 - Lemon Law. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - H.B. 366 - Situs for Assessment of Taxes. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - H.B. 367 - Telephone Detective. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - H.B. 368 - Adult Abuse. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - H.B. 369 - Spousal Abuse. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - H.B. 396 - Court Fees. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - H.B. 483 - Telephone Competition. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - H.B. 484 - Public Service Corporation Designation. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - H.B. 517 - Rental Application Fees. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - H.B. 518 - Failure to Return Security Deposits. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - H.B. 519 - Interest on Security Deposits. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - H.B. 520 - Bad Rent Check Law. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - H.B. 521 - Emergency Frequencies. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - H.B. 522 - Interexchange Telephone Companies. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - H.B. 814 - Governor's Council on Alcohol and Drug Abuse Problems. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - H.B. 875 - Indigent and Elderly Medical Assistance. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - H.B. 876 - Crime Victims Assistance. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - H.J.R. 53 - Telecommunications Industry Study. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - H.J.R. 154 - Family Life Study. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Alexandria. (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Hold. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Other. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - 1985
    - Patron Report. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Co-Patron Bills. (Box 3, Folder 24-25)
    - H.B. 519 - Security Deposits. (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - H.B. 1160 - Condo Purchase/Contract Right to Review. (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - H.B. 1161 - Finance Officer for Alexandria Historical Restoration. (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - H.B. 1314 - Telephone Resalers. (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - H.B. 1315 - Crime Victims Assistance. (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - H.B. 1316 - Radio Frequency Protection. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - H.B. 1220 - Security Deposits 5% (Remove "Q" Rate). (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - H.B. 1375 - FOIA Exemption for Rape Crisis and Battered Spouses Centers. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - H.J.R. 53 - Effects of Diverse Changes in Telecommunications Industry. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - H.J.R. 100 - Telephone Monthly Flat Rate. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - H.J.R. 240 - Telecommunications Committee. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - H.J.R. 254 - Arts Committee. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - H.J.R. 280 - Small Telephone Companies Regulatory Procedures. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - H.J.R. 342 - Arts Appreciation Month. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - H.J.R. 347 - Death of Ilka D. Dickman, M.D. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Dropped. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Removal of Cases of Unlawful Entry and Detainer. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Retaliatory Eviction. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Suspension of Drivers License. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Telephone Cooperatives. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 1986
    - Patron Report. (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Co-Patron Report. (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Co-Sponsor: House Bills. (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
    - Co-Sponsor: House Joint Resolutions. (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Co-Sponsor: House Resolutions. (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Co-Sponsor: Senate Bills. (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Co-Sponsor: Senate Joint Resolutions. (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - H.B. 18 - Alexandria City Charter. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - H.B. 235 - Sexual Harassment. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - H.B. 247 - Arts Commission. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - H.B. 248 - Tax Exemption Youth Residential Services. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - H.B. 272 - Alcoholic Content. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - H.B. 275 - Small Investor Owned Telephone Utility Act. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - H.B. 488 - Court Fines. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - H.B. 655 - Victims of Crime: Notification. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - H.B. 703 - Borrower's Right to Pay Taxes and Insurance. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - H.B. 704 - Fayette Court (Micah). (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - H.B. 726 - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - H.B. 767 - Telephone Resale of Service. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Budget Amendment - Alexandria Jail. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Budget Amendment - Gifted and Talented Programs. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Budget Amendment - NVCC Business/Industry Project. (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Budget Amendment - Old Apothecary. (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Budget Amendment - Project Discovery. (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Budget Amendment - TV Classroom. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Budget Amendment - Virginia Association of Museums. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Budget Amendment - Volunteer Bureau. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Budget Amendment - Voter Registrars Salaries. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Budget Amendments - House and Senate. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Legislation Not Introduced - American Diabetes Association Tax Exemption. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Legislation Not Introduced - Children's Trust Fund. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Legislation Not Introduced - Condo Association Notification. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Legislation Not Introduced - Harris Masonic Memorial Association Tax Exemption. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Legislation Not Introduced - Health Insurance for Elderly. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Legislation Not Introduced - Marriage License. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Legislation Not Introduced - Victim's Compensation. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - 1987
    - Patron Report. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - H.B. 491 - Reports of Alcohol and Drug Abuse on School Property. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - H.J.R. 275 - Women's History Month. (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Budget Amendments. (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Budget Amendments - Alexandria. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Budget Amendments - Miscellaneous. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Appropriations Committee. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - "How to Read and Understand the State Budget." (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 1988
    - Patron Report. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - H.B. 34 - Telecommunications Assistance for the Deaf. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - H.B. 35 - Virginia Work-Study Program. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - H.B. 429 - Visual Smoke Detectors for the Hearing Impaired. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - H.B. 431 - Workmen's Compensation Insurance Requirements. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - H.B. 432 - Adoption Assistance for Children With Special Needs. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - H.B. 433 - Adoption and Medical Assistance. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - H.B. 629, 864 - Unpaid Court Fines. (Box 7, Folder 10-13)
    - H.B. 865 - Adoption Assistance (Medicaid). (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Budget Amendments. (Box 8, Folder 2-4)
    - Budget Amendments (Prospective). (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Alexandria Legislative Package. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Bills. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Extra Copies. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - 1989
    - H.B. 439 - Parental Leave. (Box 8, Folder 9-13)
    - H.J.R. 336 - School Dropout and Self-Esteem. (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - S.B. 727 - Gun Bill. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - S.J.R. 191 - Certain Practices Among Psychiatric Professionals. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Pole Attachments. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Special Session - Taxation of Income from Public Retirement System. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 1990
    - H.B. 51 - Retail Sales and Use Tax Exemptions. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - H.B. 230 - Charitable Solicitations. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - H.B. 427 - Expansion of Drug-Free School Zones. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - H.B. 428 - Community College. (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - H.B. 510 - Interpreter Services for Hearing Impaired. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - H.B. 511 - Duties of Voter Registrars. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - H.B. 564 - Deaf Jurors. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - H.B. 565 - Victims of Crime Out-of-Pocket Reimbursement. (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - H.B. 696 - Tax on Video Rentals. (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - H.B. 1072 - Endangered Species. (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - H.J.R. 37 - Electromagnetic Leakage. (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - H.J.R. 38 - Social Services Formulas. (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - H.J.R. 74 - Braille/Blind. (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - S.B. 47 - City of Alexandria Legislative Package. (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Budget Amendments. (Box 9, Folder 19-20)
    - Budget Amendments. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - 1991
    - Alexandria. (Box 10, Folder 2-5)
    - Bills of Interest to Constituents. (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
  - 1992
    - H.J.R. 97 - Foreign-Born Needs Study. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - H.B. 940 - Parole Eligibility. (Box 10, Folder 9-13)
    - H.B. 940 - Parole Eligibility. (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
    - Constituent Correspondence. (Box 11, Folder 3-7)
  - 1993
    - Budget Amendments. (Box 11, Folder 8-9)
  - 1995
    - Patron Report. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - H.B. 1921 - HIV Testing. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - H.B. 1922 - HIV Gamete Donors. (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - H.B. 2176 - Homeless Trust Fund. (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - H.B. 2177 - Higher Education Incentive Program. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - H.B. 2178 - Equal Opportunity in Higher Education. (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - H.B. 2179 - Electoral Board/Registrars. (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - H.B. 2180 - Voter Registration/Power of Attorney. (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - H.B. 2181 - Voter Lists. (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - H.B. 2182 - Certificates of Public Need/Nursing Homes. (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - H.B. 2542 - Omnibus Educational Act. (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
    - H.J.R. 516 - Information Technology. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - H.J.R. 517 - Criminal Justice Boards. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - H.J.R. 518 - Correctional Standards. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - H.J.R. 565 - Statewide Plan for Equal Opportunity in Higher Education. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - H.J.R. 566 - Viatical Agreement. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - H.J.R. 567 - Continue HIV Study. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - H.J.R. 630 - Continuation of Young Adults Services Study. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - H.J.R. 631 - Training Service Providers. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - H.J.R. 632 - Medicaid Waiver. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Budget Amendments. (Box 12, Folder 13-14)
    - City of Alexandria. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - 1997
    - Patron Report. (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - H.B. 2078 - Campaign Finance Disclosure Reports. (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - H.B. 2271 - Conflict/Public Employees. (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - H.B. 2272 - VHDA/Local Disapproval of Housing Developments. (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - H.B. 2420 - Voter Registrars. (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - H.B. 2481 - Educational Opportunities. (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - H.B. 2484 - Virginia Arts Foundation. (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - H.J.R. 543 - Virginia Commission for the Arts. (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - 1999
    - H.B. 1611 - Relief of Joseph J. Smith III. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - H.B. 1852 - Electoral Board. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - H.B. 1853 - Voter Records. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - H.B. 1854 - Voter Registration. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - H.B. 2010 - Electronic Filings. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - H.B. 2263 - Teacher Licensure. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - H.B. [?] - Transportation Trust Fund. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - H.B. [?] - HIV Patient Assistance. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - H.J.R. 588 - English as a Second Language Study. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - H.J.R. 657 - Standards of Quality. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 13, Folder 11-12)
  - 2000
    - Patron Report. (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - H.B. 222 - Sales Tax Exemption NTI Institute for Applied Behavioral Science. (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - H.B. 223 - Tax Exemptions for Non-Profit Mental Health Organizations. (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - H.B. 224 - Tax ExemptionsL America's Promise - The Alliance for Youth, Inc. (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - H.B. 225 - Tax Exemptions: Water Environment Federation. (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - H.B. 976 - Health, Safety, and Nuisance Laws. (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - H.B. 977 - Absentee Voting. (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - H.B. 982 - HIV Premium Assistance Program. (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - H.B. 1320 - Maternal and Child Health Fund. (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - H.B. 1321 - Specialized Transportation Council (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - H.J.R. 183 - Standards of Accreditation. (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - H.J.R. 184 - ESL/LEP Students Continuing Education. (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - H.J.R. 264 - Blood-Borne Pathogens Study. (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - 2001
    - Patron Report. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - H.B. 1957 - Sales and Use Tax Exemptions for Educational Purposes. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - H.B. 2164 - Scuba Diver License Plate. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - H.B. 2207 - Determination of Vote on Voting Equipment. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - H.B. 2208 - Medical Assistance Services: Applications for Children. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - H.B. 2209 - Children's Health Insurance. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - H.B. 2210 - Choldren's Health Insurance: Waiting Period Exception. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - H.B. 2211 - Voter Registration: Cancellation of Registration. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - H.B. 2212 - Absentee Voting in Business Emergencies. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - H.B. 2233 - Record of Undervoted and Overvoted Ballots. (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - H.B. 2618 - Final Day to Register to Vote Before an Election. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - H.J.R. 629 - Early Childhood Educational and Developmental Initiatives. (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - H.J.R. 712 - Commending Wright to Read. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Budget Amendments. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - 2002
    - Patron Report. (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - H.B. 1065 - Virginia Arts Foundation. (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - H.B. 1066 - Property Loaned to Museums. (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - H.B. 1067 - Conflict of Interests. (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - H.B. 1068 - Criminal History Record/Youth Mentoring Programs. (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - H.B. 1211 - Building Code Rehad. (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - H.B. 1369 - Divorce/Annulment Racial Designation. (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - H.J.R. 168 - Early Childhood Study. (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - H.J.R. 193 - Hager Resolution. (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - H.J.R. 218 - Advancing Research and New Technologies. (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - H.J.R. 219 - Medicaid Buy-In Study. (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - H.J.R. 236 - Housing Opportunities for Disabled. (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - H.J.R. 281 - Death of Bill Perkins. (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - H.J.R. 289 - Death of Bryan Jack. (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - H.J.R. 290 - Death of Norma Steuerle. (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - H.J.R. 328 - Women's Wellness Month. (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Budget Amendments. (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - 2003
    - Patron Report. (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - H.B. 2105 - Medicaid Buy-In. (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - H.B. 2106 - Health/Vital Statistics. (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - H.B. 2107 - Recordation Tax. (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - H.B. 2568 - Presidential Primaries. (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - H.B. 2636 - ESL/SOQ. (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - H.B. 2683 - Building Rehabilitation. (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - H.J.R [?] - Death of Lois Van Valkenburgh. (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Budget Amendments. (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - 2004
    - Patron Report. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - H.B. 112 - Board of Corrections. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - H.B. 817 - Disability Commission. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - H.B. 874 - Affordable Housing (Alexandria). (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - H.B. 1256 - School Closings. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Budget Amendments. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - 2005
    - Patron Report. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - H.B. 2078 - Virginia Antiquities Act Penalties. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - H.B. 2079 - Virginia Historic Preservation. (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - H.B. 2118 - Accessible Housing. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - H.B. 2545 - Assisted Living Facilities. (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - H.B. 2546 - Air Emissions Reductions in Severe Nonattainment Areas. (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - H.B. 2547 - Fiduciaries. (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - H.B. 2761 - Student Assessments Funding. (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Budget Amendments. (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Series II. Subject Files, 1981-2006., Extent: 9 boxes. (Box 16-24)
  The subject files include awards and certificates, biographical information, newsletters, office files, photographs, press releases, programs, scrapbooks, and other materials. There are a large number of clippings, mostly from Alexandria newspapers, documenting Van Landingham's legislative activities, appearances at local events, campaign and election coverage, local and state politics, and columns written by her regarding specific issues facing the General Assembly. There are also newspaper stories relating to her involvement with the Torpedo Factory Art Center in Alexandria. In addition, the subject files contain a substantial amount of material relating to the Walt Disney Company's proposed theme park development in Prince William County, the improvement and replacement of the Woodrow Wilson Bridge, and redistricting of House of Delegates and Senate seats and congressional districts in Virginia in 1991. Van Landingham's interests in parole eligibility, sentencing guidelines, and prison conditions are also reflected in the subject files. There is a information on Suzanne (Sue) S. Kennon, an inmate at the Virginia Correctional Center for Women in Goochland, Virginia, and her parole requests and appeals, and the related subjects of the application of the 1982 Virginia "three-time-loser law," and the children of incarcerated women. There are also materials related to the conditions at VCCW, as well as materials from other inmates there, and at other facilities, regarding their specific cases. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Awards, Certificates, Honors. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Information. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Builders/Construction Industry, 1985. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Checkbook Register, 1982-1986. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1981-1990. (Box 16, Folder 5-17)
  - Clippings, 1991-1999. (Box 17, Folder 1-13)
  - Clippings, 2000-2006. (Box 18, Folder 1-7)
  - Correspondence, 1983. (Box 18, Folder 8-9)
  - Disney. (Box 18, Folder 10-15)
  - Disney. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Gun Control, 1993. (Box 19, Folder 2-4)
  - Kennon, Sue (*NOTE - PORTIONS RESTRICTED). (Box 19, Folder 5-9)
  - Literary Fund, 1987. (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters. (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Office Files, 1982-1983. (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Perinatal Drug. (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
  - Photograph - Virginia House of Delegates, 1991. (Box 28)
  - Photographs. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Press Releases, 1982-2003. (Box 20, Folder 4-18)
  - Prisons. (Box 20, Folder 19-20)
  - Prisons. (Box 21, Folder 1-10)
  - Programs. (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Provider Tax. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Recycling. (Box 22, Folder 2-3)
  - Redistricting. (Box 22, Folder 4-8)
  - Scrapbooks, 1981-1983, 1986. (Box 28-29)
  - Taxes and Assessments (*NOTE - PORTIONS RESTRICTED). (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Teen Pregnancy. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Telephone. (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Train Station. (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Transportation - Commuter Rail. (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
  - Transportation, Future of in Virginia, 1996-1997. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - University of Virginia. (Box 23, Folder 4-5)
  - "A View From the House" (Van Landingham Intro)- VHS Videotape, 2 copies. (Box 29)
  - Virginia Correctional Center for Women. (Box 23, Folder 6-12)
  - Voting. (Box 23, Folder 13)